Finding aid to the Arthur Ware Locke papers CA.MS.01135
Smith College Archives
Arthur Ware Locke papers
1927-2000
Smith College Archives
Locke, Arthur Ware
CA.MS.01135
1.438 linear feet (2 containers)
Arthur Ware Locke was Professor of Music at Smith College from 1915 to 1952. His papers contain correspondence, compositions, publications, photographs, and news clippings documenting his work.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Biographical / Historical
Arthur Ware Locke was born in 1883 in Cambridge Massachusetts to Mr. and Mrs. Warren A. Locke. He graduated from Harvard University in 1905 and studied music in Berlin for the next two years as a travelling fellow of the Harvard Graduate School. He taught music at a number of institutions, including Brown University, Washburn College, and the University of Wisconsin, before coming to Smith as Professor of Music in 1915. At Smith, Locke taught Wagner, Beethoven, and piano, as well as performing for the community in the weekly faculty concerts. Locke was also responsible for the acquisition of definitive editions of Bach, Beethoven, Brahms and Schubert for the college, a collection that was named the Locke Collection in 1969. During his time at Smith, Locke also compiled Selected Lists of Choruses for Women's Voices, which went through three editions in his lifetime. Locke retired in 1952. In 1968, his wife, Margaret Griswold Locke passed away. They had had three children together. Arthur Locke died one year later.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains photographs of Arthur Ware Locke teaching, news clippings about his career, compositions for various events at Smith College, and material related to his book, Selected Lists of Choruses for Women's Voices, including correspondence to publishers and co-author, Fassett manuscripts, and notes.
Locke, Arthur Ware
- Professor of music (1915-52), 1932-2000 (Box 929, Folder 1)
- Photographs, undated (Box 929, Folder 2)
- Publications – Selected Lists of Choruses, 1927-1946 (Box 929, Folder 3)
- Publications – Selected Lists of Choruses for Women's Voices – Correspondence A-Z, 1960-1963 (Box 929, Folder 4)
- Publications – Selected Lists of Choruses for Women's Voices – Correspondence (Locke-Fassett), 1963-1964 (Box 929, Folder 5)
- Publications – Selected Lists of Choruses for Women's Voices – Misc. Notes, 1963 (Box 929, Folder 6)
- Stravinsky's Music, undated (Box 929, Folder 7)
- Publications – Selected Lists of Women's Choruses - Manuscript, undated (Box 929, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Choral Pieces, undated (Box 929.1, Folder 1)
- Sonata for Piano and Violin, undated (Box 929.1, Folder 2)
- Misc Orchestral Pieces, undated (Box 929.1, Folder 3)
- Schubert March for Piano – Four Hands – Op. 40 a No. 6, undated (Box 929.1, Folder 4)